History 193: Tufts in American History Student Papers UA247
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
History 193: Tufts in American History Student Papers
2017 -- 2020
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
UA247
723.17 Megabytes
25 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains final papers and presentations of students enrolled in HIS193: Tufts in American History. Students in the course used the Digital Collections and Archives as a laboratory for researching and writing on topics related to campus life at Tufts from the 19th to 21st centuries century.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by students to DCA in 2018, accession UA-2018-045; 2019, accession UA-2020-041; 2020, accession UA-2020-070; and 2021, accession UA-2022-031.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series: Fall Semester 2017, Fall Semester 2018, Spring Semester 2020, and Spring Semester 2021.
Biographical / Historical
This course uses the Digital Collections and Archives as a laboratory for researching and writing on topics related to campus life at Tufts from the 19th to 21st century, including dating, sororities and fraternities, the student movement in the 1960s, the women's movements, student publications, and sports and Title IX. In this course, students complete individual research projects based on primary sources available in the archives. As of 2021, this course is taught by Virginia Drachman.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains final papers and presentations of students enrolled in HIS193: Tufts in American History. Students in the course used the Digital Collections and Archives as a laboratory for researching and writing on topics related to campus life at Tufts from the 19th to 21st centuries century.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work; Student activism
- Fall semester, 2017; UA247.001; 18.4 Megabytes; 9 Digital Object(s)
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by student last name.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains final papers and presentations of six students enrolled in HIS193 in Fall 2017.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred in 2018, accession UA-2018-045.
  - The Abolition of Curfews and Housing Regulations at Jackson College, by Julia Bell, 2017; UA247.001.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 3.5 Megabytes
    Open for research.
    Final paper
  - The Abolition of Curfews and Housing Regulations at Jackson College Presentation, by Julia Bell, 2017; UA247.001.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.3 Megabytes
    Research presentation
  - A Tradition All Their Own: The Creation and Redefinition of the Tufts Cannon and Naked Quad Run During the Vietnam War, by Emma Cook, 2017; UA247.001.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); .2 Megabytes
  - A Tradition All Their Own: The Creation and Redefinition of the Tufts Cannon and Naked Quad Run During the Vietnam War Presentation, by Emma Cook, 2017; UA247.001.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 1 Megabytes
  - The "Fremming Affair and its Legacy: An Analysis of Students for a Democratic Society at Tufts University, by Kerry Crowley, 2017; UA247.001.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); .78 Megabytes
  - "Lax on Jaxon Slacks:" The Abolition of Dress Codes at Jackson College, by Emily Hoffman, 2017; UA247.001.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); .33 Megabytes
  - "Lax on Jaxon Slacks:" The Abolition of Dress Codes at Jackson College Presentation, by Emily Hoffman, 2017; UA247.001.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.02 Megabytes
  - ROTC Expulsion, by Alexander Jaramillo, 2017; UA247.001.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); .62 Megabytes
  - Tufts University and the Vietnam War, From 1964 to 1970, by Renee LaMarche, 2017; UA247.001.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); .18 Megabytes
- Fall semester, 2018; UA247.000012; 2.77 Megabytes 3 PDFs and 2 Word documents.
  Transferred to DCA in 2019, accession UA-2020-041.
  This series contains final papers and presentations of four students enrolled in HIS193 in Fall 2018.
  - 'A Golden Era': An Investigation into the Survival and Success of Tufts College during the Great Depression, by Daniel R. Goldstein, 2018; UA247.000013
  - Modern Dating Comes to Tufts in the Early Twentieth Century, by Jae Yeun Kim, 2018; UA247.000014
  - Modern Dating Comes to Jackson College In between WWI and II Presentation, by Jae Yeun Kim, 2018; UA247.000015
    Final presentation
  - A Campus Divided: Observing the Conversation on Rape at Tufts in the 1970s, by Lauren Kim, 2018; UA247.000016
  - Judith Mears: A Woman Leader for the Tufts Weekly (1964-68), by Riane Janine Ragno, 2018; UA247.000017
- Spring semester, 2020; UA247.000018; 702 Kilobytes; 6 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains final papers written by six students enrolled in HIS193 in Spring 2020.
  - "April Fools!" The Expression of Student Frustration Through Satire in the Tufts Observer, by Luke Allocco, 2020; UA247.000019; 53.8 Kilobytes
  - Anti-Asian Racism at Tufts University in 1982: Who was Protected?, by Maxine Bell, 2020; UA247.000020; 235.2 Kilobytes
  - The Men Behind the Myth: The Origins of the Beelzebubs and Collegiate A Cappella Singing, 1962-1975, by Michael Kiang, 2020; UA247.000021; 196.1 Kilobytes
  - The Construction of Hamilton Pool, Tufts University, by John LaLime, 2020; UA247.000022; 39.2 Kilobytes
  - Tufts and the Second World War, by Laura Schmidt, 2020; UA247.000023; 26.2 Kilobytes
  - The Women of World War 1: Jackson College Sorority Women and their Patriotic Efforts in Fighting the War, by Alexa Weinstein, 2020; UA247.000024; 169.1 Kilobytes
- Spring semester, 2021; UA247.000025; 3 Digital Object(s); 444 Kilobytes
  This series contains final papers written by three students enrolled in HIS193 in Spring 2021.
  - The Limitations of the Experiment: The Experimental College and Tensions in the Tufts Student Movement, by Ruby Belle Booth, 2021; UA247.000026; 29 Kilobytes
  - The Conception, Construction, and Completion of the Henry Clay Jackson Gymnasium, by Alexis Noelle Chauvette, 2021; UA247.000027; 367 Kilobytes
  - Gynecology for Jumbos: Activism, Women's Health, and Birth Control on Tufts Campus from 1970-1972, by Catherine Rosch, 2021; UA247.000028; 47.6 Kilobytes